

3575 Rue University, Montreal, Quebec, H3A2B3

□ (+01) 4388663616 | shilei.lin@mail.mcgill.ca | s1lin.github.io | os1lin | oShilei.Lin

Summary _

A current graduate student enrolled in the Computer Science program at McGill University. Bachelor of Arts in Computer Science and Mathematics from St.John's University in 2017. Scientific Computing Researcher at SCL lab in McGill. Software Developer specialized in web-based Methodologies and Technologies.

Work & Research Experience_

McGill University

Montreal, Quebec, Canada

TEACHING ASSISTANT Jan. 2020 - Current

- Provided help for student with assignments, answered questions for labs, and graded exams.
- Demonstrated course material to the satisfaction of the course instructor.
- Worked closely with lecture instructors, prepared for the touring sessions with equivalent materials. Often engaged students to understand their needs, provided timely feedback to instructors, and helped invigilate exams.

Chengdu Zhishicheng Education Co, LTD.

Chengdu, Sichuan, China

ACADEMIC ADMINISTRATOR AND SYSTEM MANAGER

Feb. 2018 - Jul. 2019

- Scheduled Courses, collected and analyzed students' transcripts and communicated with teachers. Coordinated student and school activities, courses and projects.
- Gave advise to students on their curriculum plans and oversight student activities.
- · Ensured the project achieves educational administrative objectives, formulated the project milestones.
- · Developed management schemes for different needs for the software. Engaged with teachers and students to modify software accordingly.

Guoxin YoueData Co, LTD.

Chengdu, Sichuan, China

Junior Java Developer

- Part of the development team for a data management platform based on the disparate system.
- Executed process analysis and system deployments and assisted the clients by providing technique advise, testing software and giving enduser training sessions.
- Actively participated as a member of the project team in carrying out multi-aspects of the software requirements.

Saint John's University

Collegeville, Minnesota, USA

Undergraduat Research Assistant

Jan. 2016 - May. 2017

Jun. 2017 - Feb. 2018

- Conducted research in the field of high-performance computing.
- Acquired and utilized knowledge including scientific computing, then formally presented, interpreted and analyzed quantitative and qualitative data as results.
- A member of the computational science and engineering (CES) research team.

Education

McGill University

M.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Montreal, Quebec, Canada Aug. 2019 - Exp. Aug. 2021

- Currently study at School of Computer Science.
- Affiliate with Scientific Computing Lab, supervising by Dr. Xiaowen Chang.
- Modules included: Algorithmic Game Theory (A-), Modern Computer Games (A-), Optimization, and Applied Machine Learning.
- Current GPA: 3.70.

SAINT JOHN'S UNIVERSITY

Collegeville, Minnesota, USA

Jan. 2014 - May. 2017

B.A. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND MATHEMATICS

- Awarded with International Student Scholarship for 4 years, and Dean's List in academic year 2015 and 2016.
- Modules included: Numerical Analysis(A), Databases(A), Mathematical Modeling(A), Computer Algorithms(A), Computer Systems(A) and Differential Equations (AB), Data Mining and management (AB).
- Final GPA: 3.73 with honor Cum Laude

Skills

Programming Java, Python, Spring Framework/Boot, Hibernate, Vue, MySQL

Data Engineering Apache Hadoop (Basic Knowledge)

Tools Idea, Git, Visual Studio, Matlab, Mathematica

Languages Chinese, English

SEPTEMBER 21, 2020 SHILEI LIN